Megan De Luca

Ottawa, ON | 613-698-6300 | megandeluca27@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/deluca-megan | github.com/mdeluca13 | mdeluca13.github.io/Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in Business and Psychology earning a Certificate in Full Stack Web Development from Carleton University. Strong passion for problem-solving and developing creative solutions. Vast experience working in fast paced environments and with diverse teams to resolve the issue at hand and exceed expectations.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Technical Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, MySQL, NoSQL, APIs, Node.js, OOP, Express.js, ORM, MVC, PWA, React, MERN, State, GraphQL, Bootstrap, Handlebars, NPM, Inquirer, Sequelize, MYSQL2, GitHub, Heroku, Visual Studio Code, Microsoft Suite, Google Suite

PROJECTS

Tech Blog | https://github.com/mdeluca13/tech-blog | https://mdeluca-tech-blog.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: Developed site where users can login and create an account to be able to create posts, and add comments to other posts.
- Role: Sole Author
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Handlebars, MySQL, Express.js, MVC, Node.js, Visual Studio Code, Heroku, GitHub

Coding Empire Conference | https://github.com/mdeluca13/coding-empire-conference |

https://coding-empire-conference.herokuapp.com

- Summary: Developed site where users can learn about talks held at the conference, choose to attend or not attend a talk, ask questions for a talk, and add, edit and delete your own talks while being logged into the site.
- Role: Author of MySQL Database, Models, Seeds, Public JavaScript files, API Routes, Sessions, and Sequelize
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Handlebars, MySQL, Express.js, MVC, Node.js, Visual Studio Code, Heroku, GitHub

E-Commerce Backend | https://github.com/mdeluca13/e-commerce-backend

- Summary: Developed a MySQL and Node.js program that allows the user to GET, ADD, UPDATE, and DELETE Category, Product and Tag information from their e-commerce backend database.
- Role: Author of Routes
- Tools: Node.js, Sequelize, MySQL, Express, MySQL2, Visual Studio Code, GitHub

EXPERIENCE

IT Administrator | Taggart Group of Companies | Ottawa, ON

January 2023

- Present

- Implemented new inventory system to purchase, track and maintain inventory of all technology for the six companies within Taggart Group
- Manage department projects by coordinating between Apps, Service and Networking teams to ensure on time delivery
- Maintain all IT department timecards to ensure their time is being billed to the correct project
- Troubleshoot reported issues to determine the root cause and work with team to determine solution
- Ensure all purchased items have an approved invoice for Accounts Payable to process

Administrative Assistant | Ainsworth | Ottawa, ON

November 2022 - December

- 2022
 - Reviewed Purchase Orders and Purchase Card Transactions on Metrix Service Management and Oracle JD Edwards software
 to ensure transactions were allocated to a Work Order or Project, and all were properly billed so the Ainsworth books were
 balanced
 - Dispatched HVAC and Building Automation Technicians to service requests and preventative maintenance calls
 - Conceptualized Revenue Report Spreadsheets to estimate future revenue and targets based on prior trends

Support Advisor | Shopify | U.S. West

July 2021 -

February 2022

- Identified and resolved issues that merchants reachout with over phone, chat or email, as well as offered analysis of their store to find ways Shopify could allow their business to grow
- Collaborated with my Team, other US West Support Advisors, and escalated teams to find the correct information to resolve a Merchant's issue
- Assisted teammates with their questions on Merchant issues as well as the team personal email queue to ensure Merchants received accurate and timely information

Art Gallery Director | Park West Gallery | Worldwide

November 2016 - April

2020

• Experience working on Norwegian, Princess, and Carnival Cruise Lines across 37 countries (4 of 7 Continents)

- Sold \$1.5M+ worth of artwork to 2,000 clients often being staffed to the highest revenue opportunity ships in order to maximize the revenue for the gallery
- Strong work ethic demonstrated by working every day for six to nine months at a time, keeping morale and performance consistent throughout my time on the ship
- Supervised a team of 20 diversely cultured staff, tailoring my leadership to the teammates preference in order to maximize the operational and financial performance of the gallery
- Managed the entire sales lifecycle by ensuring onboard inventory meets the gallery needs on a daily basis, engaging with vendors and corporate staff, along with the bookkeeping in order to record and fulfill all transactions

Activities Coordinator & Receptionist | Thorncliffe Retirement Residence, ON June 2016 – November 2016

- Planned, organized, and coordinated all activities for the 65 residents of Thorncliffe Place including activities for families to
 visit and participate in while also creating opportunities for residents to interact with one another in order to increase resident
 morale
- Answered and directed all calls, assisted all walk-ins with their inquiries, and directed all nurses to requests or emergencies from residents

Athletic Department Associate | St. Lawrence University | Canton, NY

January 2013 – May 2016

• Independently opened and closed the athletic facilities with 500+ daily visitors, while also serving as a strength training and nutritional resource for members

Intern, Life Skills | NYSARC Transitions | Canton, NY

September 2015 – December 2015

• Taught and assisted life skills classes for individuals with developmental disabilities through unique communication skills such as nutrition, safety, and social norms as well as investing the time to build meaningful relationships with the NYSARC participants in order to identify an individual's specific needs and learning opportunities

Assistant Coordinator, Youth Centers | City of Ottawa | Ottawa, ON

June 2013 – August 2015

• Supervised participants, site coordination, cash handling, advertising, public relations, and first aid

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Certificate Carleton University Ottawa, ON

January 2023 -

Present

Bachelor of Science, Magna Cum Laude, Business & Psychology St. Lawrence University Canton, NY August 2012 – May 2016

<u>Honors:</u> Psychology International Honors Society [Psi Chi]; Dean's List; International Student Scholarship; Lieutenant Governor Community Service Award; Study Abroad Research Grant focusing on Positive Psychology, Copenhagen Study Abroad Program; Founder and President of the Humane Society Club; Intern for NYSARC Transitions

<u>Thesis Topic:</u> Researched the influence of Title IX training on the tendency to blame a victim of sexual assault with the use of a victim blame questionnaire, Rape Myth Acceptance Scale, and an Implicit Association Test leveraging psychological, statistical, computer programming, and research methods in order to balance quantitative and qualitative findings prior to authoring a final paper and presenting to the department leadership